ERIK HIRSCH

Apple Valley, CA | P: 760 420-4308 | E: ehirsch760@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/e-hirsch

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Personable, self-motivated Full Stack Web Developer with 4 years of experience in project management and 2 years of web development roles. Possesses a solid foundation in creating full stack web and mobile applications, graphic design and programming, and general IT Support procedures demonstrated through experience as a Developer at Third Project Development. Outstanding communicator able to work with diverse colleagues to produce value from effective problem-solving and creating innovative solutions.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Full.	Stack	Weh	Deve	opment

- Web-Development Tools & AWS
- UI Wireframe Designing

User-Authentication Testing

- Consulting
- Policy Compliance
- Ecommerce Websites
- System Integration Testing
- User-Requirement Analysis

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PBP GLOBAL | REMOTE | 2021 - PRESENT

Promotional Goods Ecommerce Website (June 2021)

A fully integrated ecommerce website developed on the Magento2 platform. Utilized an AWS Linux based server to query API routes to retrieve product data, saved into an SQL database.

- Responsible for system integration testing, testing application, creating user acceptance testing scenarios, fixing defects, and retesting the fixes in strict adherence to 100% of goals and vision during 2021.
- Bolstered expertise in utilizing AWS technologies, including LightSail, S3, and CloudFront. Successfully identified areas for improvement with accuracy and optimized productivity throughout tenure.
- Executed product updates daily utilizing CRON jobs on a Debian10 server. Employed excellent task prioritization and problem-solving skills when attending and contributing to development processes.
- Developed a UI for the database allowing admins to search the database using filters. Innovatively generated functionalities
 for rresults displayed in a catalog style with pagination and a product page.
- Generated multiple API endpoints enabling third parties to retrieve data required for integration.
- Maintained high standards of professional expertise during work processes and idea-sharing discussions during tenure.
- Entrusted with the responsibility to handle MySQL database containing over 140,000 products with over 10 million rows of data
- Skillfully examined requests and needs to provide bespoke solutions.

Time2Fly (April 2021)

A utility application for flight attendants to track hours and prevent unapproved overtime.

- Designed and developed a responsive mobile application built with React Native in three months. Effectively tailored to aid
 flight attendants in finding the most efficient ways to track hours during tenure.
- Analyzed user requirements to create user authentication utilizing Firebase, sustaining updated knowledge of web applications and IT processes in creating and designing the authentication schema.
- Reviewed specification requirements to assist in the designing of UI wireframes. Integrated functions for users to update
 passwords and usernames individually.

Rick Kittson Hardwood Flooring (March 2021)

A company landing page that provides information on services provided and establishes a simple contact method for potential clients.

- Frontend application features smooth and polished UI and visually appealing transitions and animations.
- Utilizes Gulp to compile and deploy static assets.

TRILOGY EDUCATION SERVICES| REMOTE | 2022- PRESENT

Teaching Assistant | Tutor

- Foster critical thinking and independent problem-solving abilities of students learning new web development concepts.
- Topics covered include HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Node, Express, MySQL, MongoDB, ORMs, and React.js.

THIRD PROJECT DEVELOPMENT | REMOTE | 2020-PRESENT

Freelance Developer

- Developed full-stack web and mobile applications according to client's request. Consulted with clients to determine the best course of action for applications.
- Analyzed user requirements and converted requirements to design documents leveraging excellent communication and interpersonal skills to steward professional relationships with all clients for increased retention rates.

US DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE - BUREAU OF CENSUS | VICTORVILLE, CA | 2020

Enumerator

• Engaged and connected with the public, employing strong communication skills to expedite operations. Showcased the potential to work 100% independently to complete daily tasks, leveraging expertise to enhance practices.

UNITED PARCEL SERVICE | VICTORVILLE, CA | 2019-2020

Delivery Driver

• Streamlined operational procedures while delivering packages to customers in a timely and professional manner. Recognized for strong work ethic, awarded by management for achieving highest performance.

RICK KITTSON HARDWOOD FLOORING | IRVINE, CA | 2015-2019

Project Manager

 Supervised a small team of craftsmen to uphold quality and complete projects well before deadlines. Adhered to the company's goals and visions, measuring project performance to identify areas for improvement.

EDUCATION

UCLA Extension, Los Angeles, CA: 2020

Full Stack Web Development – (A)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Course Studied: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & React.

Victor Valley Collage, Victorville, CA: 2012-2013

Management Certificate of Completion – Certification

Course Studied: Accounting, Economics, Computer Literacy, Human Resource Management, Legal Environment of Business, Business Math, and Business Communications.

ADDITIONAL CREDENTIALS

Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Access, Publisher) / Languages

	(HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, PHP, XML) / Technologies (Node, React, Next.js,		
	React Native, Redux, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, Atlas, Firebase,		
	Express, jQuery, BootStrap, Semantic, Material UI, Reactstrap, React Bootstrap, AJAX,		
	AWS, PHP, Debian, Handlebars.js)		
LANGUAGES			
PROFESSIONAL	Scrimba: The React Boot Camp (2020), Tricky Parts of JavaScript (2020), Learn		
DEVELOPMENT	Regular Expressions (2020), Building Reusable React (2021), Responsive Web Design		
	Bootcamp (2021), Learn Tailwind CSS (2022)		
	Amazon Web Services: The React Boot Camp (2020), Tricky Parts of JavaScript		
	(2020), Learn Regular Expressions (2020), Building Reusable React (2021), Responsive		
	Web Design Bootcamp (2021)		